ANDREW DING

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

PROFILE

I am a full-stack web developer passionate about imagining then creating applications that are simple yet provide a great user experience. I enjoy the AHA moment when coding and immersing myself into many different web development technologies.

I feel very comfortable working in environments where I can fulfill many different roles and freely share my opinions with other coworkers.

I like to take my time in understanding businesses and their processes, but I am generally very fast in picking up new technologies and becoming proficient with them. Working in many different kinds of industries and companies has made me adaptable to many different kinds of environments as well as instilling a sense of fun in what I do.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TECHNICAL BUSINESS ANALYST

EORIGINAL | 2013-2016

- Main contact with clients to integrate eOriginal electronic signing software into their application
- Troubleshoot customer issues using Splunk to check error logs and fixing programming code or XML
- Trained customers on software API by providing demos, suggesting workflows and writing documentation
- Worked with development t3eams by fixing bugs and submitting change requests in JIRA
- Built utilities developed in PHP to perform large batch workflows and created demo websites
- Maintained REST API website at http://eodtest.eoriginal.com and tested SOAP API using SOAPU UI

ECONOMIC DATA SYSTEMS SPECIALIST

INTERNATIONAL MONETARY FUND | 2012-2013

- Maintained frameworks for database applications in Excel
- Solved technical issues for Economists which involved large data sets
- Built and maintained macros to increase efficiency for Fund operations
- Communicated with IT teams to deliver software in an IMF image-based environment
- Achieved highest number of customer support tickets resolved during tenure



1713 Piccard Drive, Rockville, MD



240.271.2888



andy.ding89@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/ading1



https://github.com/andyding1

EDUCATION

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

DecodeMTL 2016

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN ECONOMICS

New York University 2007-2010

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA (MAGNET PROGRAM)

Montgomery Blair 2003-2007

TECHNICAL

JavaScript	NodeJS
React	Express
HTML5	CSS3
jQuery	Socket.io
EJS	CLI
Git	Github
MySQL	Sequelize
Webpack	JSX
Babel	VBA

ANDREWDING

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

PROJECTS

STREAMR

CUSTOMER BUILT CHAT AND VIDEO STREAMING APPLICATION

- Main Technologies: JavaScript, Socket.io, React, Express, Webpack/Babel/JSX, CSS3, WebRTC
- https://streamrcast.herokuapp.com

FUGGEDABOUDDIT

REDDIT CLONE

- Main Technologies: JavaScript, Express, Sequelize, MySQL, React, JSX, EJS, Password Hashing, Cookies/Session ID, jQuery, CSS3
- https://blooming-sierra-23459.herokuapp.com/

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: Advanced
MANDARIN: Intermediate
SPANISH: Beginner
KOREAN: Elementary

SOFTWARE

SOAP UI Splunk JIRA Adobe Photoshop Excel SharePoint